<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Andre Fellipe</title><link href="https://andrefellipe.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://andrefellipe.com/feeds/all-en.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://andrefellipe.com/</id><updated>2020-03-06T14:02:00-03:00</updated><subtitle>made on the internet</subtitle><entry><title>Day One</title><link href="https://andrefellipe.com/amazon.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-03-06T14:02:00-03:00</published><updated>2020-03-06T14:02:00-03:00</updated><author><name>Andre Fellipe da Silva</name></author><id>tag:andrefellipe.com,2020-03-06:/amazon.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;After graduating from college, I became an Amazonian. Let's talk a little bit about this process and this awesome beginning. This post was written to the sound of the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Top_Gun_(soundtrack)"&gt;soundtrack from Top Gun&lt;/a&gt;. You can listen one of the songs &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=siwpn14IE7E"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm an Amazonian now.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="work"></category><category term="amazon"></category><category term="work"></category></entry><entry><title>Quant boys, quant boys, whatcha gonna do</title><link href="https://andrefellipe.com/cfm-2019.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-01-26T23:20:00-03:00</published><updated>2020-01-26T23:20:00-03:00</updated><author><name>Andre Fellipe da Silva</name></author><id>tag:andrefellipe.com,2020-01-26:/cfm-2019.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;At the end of 2019, I participated in another data science competition, this time related to finance. This post was written to the sound of The Police's &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Outlandos_d%27Amour"&gt;Outlandos d'Amour'&lt;/a&gt;. You can listen one of the songs &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nH0vjLwMyc4"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I participated in my second data science competition last month and it was again a worthy experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My team, composed of myself and two friends, competed with 131 teams from all over the world at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.cfm.fr/"&gt;Capital Fund Management&lt;/a&gt;’s 2019 supervised machine learning challenge, hosted at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/%C3%89cole_normale_sup%C3%A9rieure_(Paris)"&gt;ENS&lt;/a&gt;’s &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://challengedata.ens.fr/"&gt;Challenge Data&lt;/a&gt; platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal was to predict sign accuracy using anonymized US stock returns data, a highly stochastic dataset with 1 million lines and 74 columns (training + test).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group split between different tasks such as feature engineering, essaying neural network architectures (my part) and AutoML frameworks, and applying traditional ML methods like GBMs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our best submission was a CNN-based one that unfortunately overfit the training data a little, which gave us the final ranking of 15.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did this in less than a month. I believe that we will participate again this year and we're going to go even further since we have more time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first place wins an iPad. I never had one and, oh boy, I want it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After winning in 2020, all three of us then can become quant traders and be filthy rich for the rest of our lives. Finance is awesome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned next year to find out if the plan goes accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="portfolio"></category><category term="statistics"></category><category term="data science"></category><category term="python"></category></entry><entry><title>This is the end, beautiful friend</title><link href="https://andrefellipe.com/ufrn-final-project.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-12-01T15:30:00-03:00</published><updated>2019-12-01T15:30:00-03:00</updated><author><name>Andre Fellipe da Silva</name></author><id>tag:andrefellipe.com,2019-12-01:/ufrn-final-project.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;I've presented my final project at the university last week. This post was written to the sound of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Doors_(album)"&gt;The Doors'&lt;/a&gt; eponymous album. You can listen one of the songs &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BXqPNlng6uI"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, I'm only a few days away from officially becoming an electrical engineer. The final step was taken last thursday. I did my presentation and the professors loved it. One of the them even invited me to do my master's degree with him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's the official photo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Professor Max Chianca, myself and professor Marcos Dias." class="align-center" src="images/08-01-Final-Project-Presentation.jpeg" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you didn't realized yet from older posts, I'm always the tall one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My final project was a very easy one. Last july, during my Electrical Substations class, the professor suggested that developing a program to design grounding grids for substations alongside a tool for soil stratification would be a good idea for a final project. I thought to myself &amp;quot;Hey, I can do this very quickly&amp;quot; and I did it in two weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally, I did it on MATLAB. In the beginning of september I think, I decided to develop an API using Django and put it up on Heroku. Then, I created a small form to consume the API and used Heroku again to leave it online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MATLAB and Python code can be found on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/andrefellipe/esd"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and the live website is on this weird &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://grounding-design.herokuapp.com/index.html"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The math behind everything is not very difficult and I'm not going to dwell on it much. Basically, we have to minimize this function to do the soil stratification with two layers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Least squares equation for two-layer soil stratification." class="align-center" src="images/08-02-Equation.png" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, there's a block diagram on the standard IEEE 80-2000 that I followed to check if the grounding grid has adequate touch and step voltages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Design procedure block diagram." class="align-center" src="images/08-03-Design-Procedure-Block-Diagram.png" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though this is not a difficult project, I liked because it was something that was done very quickly. I loved because I did it very early and had the time to focus on more important things for my career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need a simple tool to do soil stratification and check if your rectangular grounding grid is safe, you're good to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm a electrical engineer now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's see what the future holds.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="portfolio"></category><category term="matlab"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="ufrn"></category></entry><entry><title>Is it just me, or is it hot in here?</title><link href="https://andrefellipe.com/ufrn-data-science-comp-2019.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-11-20T23:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2019-11-20T23:00:00-03:00</updated><author><name>Andre Fellipe da Silva</name></author><id>tag:andrefellipe.com,2019-11-20:/ufrn-data-science-comp-2019.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Let's talk about my first participation on a data science competition. This post was written to the sound of The Killers' &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hot_Fuss"&gt;Hot Fuss&lt;/a&gt;. You can listen one of the songs &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gGdGFtwCNBE"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A colleague of mine invited me to create a team to win the 2019 UFRN Data Science Competition last month. I've never participated in one before and I thought that it was a cool experience. Our five-person group had a couple of days to do any kind of analysis on meteorological data provided by INMET, the government agency responsible for this kind of stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had to move quickly and precisely to bring to the public a creative analysis of a lot of data - basically everything related to temperatures, humidity, wind and similar variables from 1961 to today from every part of Brazil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We visualized the impact that this year's Amazon fires had on the data through geospatially visualizing temperature differences according to a baseline, running a PCA and investigating spatial patterns, and forecasting temperatures to look for anomalies. My job was to do the last part using this cool tool from Facebook called &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://facebook.github.io/prophet/docs/quick_start.html"&gt;Prophet&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, we came up short and got second place. I honestly believe that we should have won it and one member of my team even argued with the judges a little bit, but to no avail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a cool debut, though. Right now, we are getting prepared to try again in similar competitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most unfortunate part of everything was the fact that when we got to the front to receive our medals, there were two cameras, one from one of the professors and the official one of the event. I didn't notice that and put my focus on the professor's one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, yeah, I look kind of stupid in the picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="The whole team receiving the medals." class="align-center" src="images/07-01-Team-Picture.jpeg" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus, sometimes I forget how tall I am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final presentation and all of the code can be found on GitHub. You can access it with this &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/vitorsr/ccd"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And through this &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://marcusnunes.me/posts/resultados-da-competicao-de-ciencia-de-dados-da-ufrn-2019/"&gt;one&lt;/a&gt;, you can check out more information about the competition. If you know brazilian portuguese, that is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: From left to right in the picture, we have André L., Ianca, Prof. Nunes¹, Vítor, &lt;em&gt;moi&lt;/em&gt; and Mariana. We are the &lt;strong&gt;weeee&lt;/strong&gt; team!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;¹ Prof. Nunes was one of the judges.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="portfolio"></category><category term="statistics"></category><category term="data science"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="ufrn"></category></entry><entry><title>E&amp;Q Online</title><link href="https://andrefellipe.com/eq.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-01T17:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2019-05-01T17:00:00-03:00</updated><author><name>Andre Fellipe da Silva</name></author><id>tag:andrefellipe.com,2019-05-01:/eq.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;A brief description of one freelance project I've just did and how it came about. This post was written to the sound of The Clash's &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/London_Calling"&gt;London Calling&lt;/a&gt;. You can listen one of the songs &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ertt3o1x65c"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;During the first semester of 2018, I was an intern at a small local company. The company's name is &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.engenhariaequalidade.com.br/"&gt;Engenharia &amp;amp; Qualidade&lt;/a&gt; and it has been around for more than two decades. It has 10 employees as of May/2019, including the two main partners, and a long range of services that goes from structured cabling to studies of grounding and soil resistivity testing of substations. Basically, the company can solve anything in the fields of electrical installations and telecommunications thanks to the expertise of its two owners. Its major client is one of the biggest (if not the biggest) supermarket chains of my state, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.nordestao.com.br/"&gt;Nordestão&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my internship, I was responsible for the budgets and, sometimes, the supervision of the execution of some projects. As you may already know, there was a lot of Excel and AutoCAD involved. It was a brilliant experience, but, after my six months there, I came to the conclusion that this would not be something that I would like to do for a living.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to not renew my contract after one semester. During my time there, I automated a lot of the tasks on the spreadsheets that the company had, but there was a gap because we used a lot of different management tools. Excel for the budget, an old software made with VB to manage the clients and the warehouse, a physical book that the employees signed with the worked hours, etc. One of my ideas after dealing with all of that was to replace everything with something that could unify everything the company did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wasn't able to implement the system while I was an intern because my actual job (budgets and supervision of projects) didn't allowed me the time. This year, however, I approached the owners with this idea and they thought it would be great if I developed a website with all of necessary functionalities. We agreed on a price and, during the months of march and april, I've developed E&amp;amp;Q Online, a website hosted at the company own server to internal use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the login screen:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="The login screen." class="align-center" src="images/06-01-EQ-01.png" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is the homepage after the user logs in:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="The homepage after the login screen." class="align-center" src="images/06-02-EQ-02.png" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the agreement between me and the owners, I am going to be very selective of what parts of the website I am going to discuss here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, there's nine areas in the platform: &lt;strong&gt;Log&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Users&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Suppliers&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Clients&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Transport&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Warehouse&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Proposals&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Orders&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Accounts&lt;/strong&gt;. Let's do a brief rundown of each:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="log"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Log&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, the users can register when they arrive at the company, when they go out to lunch, when they return and when they leave. Also, the users are able to register any missing day. The users in the &lt;strong&gt;Administrator&lt;/strong&gt; category can see, update or delete the records and missing days from all of the users. If the user is not a part of this category, he can only see his own records.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's the screen where the user can choose what's the type of logging that he's doing it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="The screen where the user can choose the type of logging." class="align-center" src="images/06-03-EQ-03.png" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the user chooses the first option, he's going to register that he has arrived at the company. After the confirmation, a new record is created with the current timestamp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="The screen where the user can log in." class="align-center" src="images/06-04-EQ-04.png" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I said before, an administrator can see all of the records in a very friendly manner. He's able to search for any record by using any parameter (the name of the user, the date, the type of entry, etc) and he can update or delete any record:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="The screen with all records." class="align-center" src="images/06-05-EQ-05.png" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The user can also create a record of absence if he missed a day:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="The screen where the user can register an absence." class="align-center" src="images/06-06-EQ-06.png" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And an administrator can see all absences. In this particular print, there isn't one registered yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="The screen where the user can see all absences." class="align-center" src="images/06-07-EQ-07.png" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="users"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Users&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Users section, an administrator can create, update or delete an user:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="The screen where the user can see all registered users." class="align-center" src="images/06-08-EQ-08.png" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, as you can see, the users can alter their passwords. An important part of the &lt;strong&gt;Users&lt;/strong&gt; section is that every week an email is sent to the administrators with the due date of the users' documents. This is relevant because they can see when the document is going to expire and renew it at the right time. Before E&amp;amp;Q Online, the company was not used to keep track of the due dates. So, when a project showed up, part of the workforce would not be able to work because some certification was expired. Right now, the administrators receive a list informing how many days are left, as you can see below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Example of the email that the administrators receive with the users' documents and their due dates." class="align-center" src="images/06-09-EQ-09.png" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="clients-and-suppliers"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Clients and Suppliers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These two sections are basically the same. Create, update and delete the clients and the suppliers of the company. It's worth nothing that one of the most annoying parts of the project was finding out how to retrieve the database already in use in the old software to put it on the website. There where more than one thousand clients and suppliers combined in the old database and the data was in a different setup than the one that we need here, since we'll be connecting these clients and suppliers to other parts of the website. Importing the data from the Access database to the MySQL one that the site uses took almost a full afternoon of work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="The screen where the user can see all registered suppliers." class="align-center" src="images/06-10-EQ-10.png" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="transport"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Transport&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section is divided in &lt;strong&gt;Vehicles&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Travels&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Refuels&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Maintenances&lt;/strong&gt;. Here, we can create, update or delete each one of those things. Below you can see a screenshot of a refuel where the gas station listed is from the registered &lt;strong&gt;Suppliers&lt;/strong&gt; section:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="The screen where the user can see all registered refuels." class="align-center" src="images/06-11-EQ-11.png" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An old problem that has been solved is related to the inspections of the tools that are in the cars. Since the workers are in movement everyday, they need to keep equipment from the warehouse inside the cars and the company needs to ocasionally check if everything that was taken from the warehouse is in the car. If, for instance, a worker loses a screwdriver, the company needs to know and charge him for the slip. That's why in the &lt;strong&gt;Vehicles&lt;/strong&gt; section each vehicle has an inspection button where the user (generally it's the job of an intern to do the inspection) can see a list of the current tools there and check if everything matches. The list of current tools is automatically generated, a feature that we will see in the following section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="warehouse"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Warehouse&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The warehouse has more than 1.500 products and tools that the company can sell or use in a project. Here, we can basically create, update or delete a product, move the project, keep track of every movement and generate the SPED report, a list with the products and important information that the company needs to send every year to the &lt;em&gt;Receita Federal&lt;/em&gt;, our version of the IRS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see below, there's three important buttons to move products around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can make the products go in the warehouse (if we buy a 10 meters of cable and add it to the warehouse, this is the option).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can make products go from the warehouse to a service (if we need to take 3 meters of cable and use it in a project, this is the option), we can also make products go from the warehouse to a vehicle or a toolbox (as we kind of pointed out in the section before this one, this is how we keep track of the tools inside the vehicles).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, in the third button, we can return products from a car, a toolbox or a service to the warehouse (if we took 3 meters of cable to use it on a project, but only needed one, we can return two so that we can appropriately charge the client only the one that was used).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="The screen where the user can see all options in the Warehouse section." class="align-center" src="images/06-12-EQ-12.png" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this example below, we are moving 20 meters of cable that will be used in a project registered (more about orders of service later):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="An example of how to move a product out from the warehouse to a service." class="align-center" src="images/06-13-EQ-13.png" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see in the screenshot below, all of these movements can be seen in this section of the website:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="The screen where the user can see all registered movements." class="align-center" src="images/06-14-EQ-14.png" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can also generate the data that the company has to send to the government every year. Here's a snippet of this report:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="The screen where the user can see all registered movements." class="align-center" src="images/06-15-EQ-15.png" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To finish, there's the &lt;strong&gt;Toolbox&lt;/strong&gt; subsection, but it's very similar to the &lt;strong&gt;Vehicles&lt;/strong&gt; one. You can create, update and delete toolboxes and make inspections of its contents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="proposals"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Proposals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the section where we develop the budgets for the services and generate business proposals to send the clients. It's also where we can add services and update their prices. If the company adds to its catalog of services, for instance, &amp;quot;Install photovoltaic panel&amp;quot; and charges R$ 1.000,00 per panel, we can add here so that we can use it in the proposal. Or, in another instance, if the price of &amp;quot;Certification Test for CAT. 6 cable&amp;quot; goes up, we need to update it so that we can make the more recent proposals with the new price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To formulate a budget, we need to choose who is the client that we're sending the proposal and list all of the products and services that are needed to do the project. After that, the website calculates how much the material is going to cost, how much the services are going to cost, how much would it cost to do it during business hours and how much would it cost to do it out of the business hours (more expensive).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="The screen where the user can calculate the total of a proposal - part 01." class="align-center" src="images/06-16-EQ-16.png" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="The screen where the user can calculate the total of a proposal - part 02." class="align-center" src="images/06-17-EQ-17.png" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all of the prices calculated, the user can create a business proposal to sent it via email to the client and generate lists with the materials and the services needed to this project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="The screen with an example of a proposal." class="align-center" src="images/06-18-EQ-18.png" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="The screen with an example of a list of materials." class="align-center" src="images/06-19-EQ-19.png" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The example above is totally random.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="orders"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Orders&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a proposal is accepted, when the workers go out to execute the project, we need to generate an order. This is what this section is all about. We can update the status of the order (if it's ongoing or if it's finished), we can generate a list with all of the products used in the order (based on the movements that we did at the &lt;strong&gt;Warehouse&lt;/strong&gt; section) and we can print the order so that the workers can take it to the field and fill the informations that the company need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="The screen with an example of an order." class="align-center" src="images/06-20-EQ-20.png" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="The screen with an example of a list of materials that went out to the service." class="align-center" src="images/06-21-EQ-21.png" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="accounts"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Accounts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section is simply about creating, updating and deleting accounts, meaning bills to pay and bills to receive. That's it. Just a few CRUDs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="final-thoughts"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's everything. I've tried to summarize the main points of this project. It's a basic, but very functional HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP and MySQL combo. There's a couple of libraries and plugins that helped a lot, like jQuery, Bootstrap, RainTPL, Composer, PHPMailer and a couple of others that I don't recall at this moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The expectation is that we can increase the company's productivity with the website and I'm very confident that this will be achieved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to know more about the details of the implementation, you can contact me at &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:andrefellipern&amp;#64;gmail.com"&gt;andrefellipern&amp;#64;gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="portfolio"></category><category term="freelance"></category><category term="html"></category><category term="css"></category><category term="javascript"></category><category term="php"></category></entry><entry><title>Hello, OpenCV and Java</title><link href="https://andrefellipe.com/opencv-java.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-08-29T16:50:00-03:00</published><updated>2018-10-03T23:40:00-03:00</updated><author><name>Andre Fellipe da Silva</name></author><id>tag:andrefellipe.com,2018-08-29:/opencv-java.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;A tutorial to use OpenCV with Java. This post was written to the sound of Hall &amp;amp; Oates' &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Big_Bam_Boom"&gt;Big Bam Boom&lt;/a&gt;. You can listen one of the songs &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=s_8KR-n2fBQ"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This tutorial will not teach you how to compile your own OpenCV using the source code. I recommend that you try this at a future date for learning purposes. At this moment, let's try a different approach. I am using Ubuntu 18.04 and this tutorial will only work for distributions of the Linux operating system. You will see why below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I expect that you have a general knowledge about Java. If you know nothing about it so far, just follow the instructions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's dive in!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="checking-if-you-have-java"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Checking if you have Java&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open the terminal (ctrl + alt + T).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run the following command to check if you already have Java:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="gp"&gt;$&lt;/span&gt; java -version
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are good to go if you see something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="go"&gt;java version &amp;quot;1.8.0_181&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="go"&gt;Java(TM) SE Runtime Environment (build 1.8.0_181-b13)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="go"&gt;Java HotSpot(TM) 64-Bit Server VM (build 25.181-b13, mixed mode)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may have another version of Oracle's Java or OpenJDK, but this should not be a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do not see the message above or something similar, you will need to install Java. If you can see the message, jump to the next section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run the following commands to install Oracle's Java 8:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="gp"&gt;$&lt;/span&gt; sudo add-apt-repository ppa:webupd8team/java
&lt;span class="gp"&gt;$&lt;/span&gt; sudo apt-get update
&lt;span class="gp"&gt;$&lt;/span&gt; sudo apt-get install oracle-java8-installer
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run the &lt;strong&gt;java -version&lt;/strong&gt; command again to make sure everything is fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="download-opencv"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Download OpenCV&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run the following command to install the OpenCV library:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="gp"&gt;$&lt;/span&gt; sudo apt-get install libopencv-dev
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="creating-our-first-program"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Creating Our First Program&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using your favorite text editor, create a file named &lt;strong&gt;HelloOpenCVJava.java&lt;/strong&gt;. I am using &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vim_(text_editor)"&gt;Vim&lt;/a&gt;, so the command would be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="gp"&gt;$&lt;/span&gt; vim HelloOpenCVJava.java
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, copy and paste the following code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;org.opencv.core.Core&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="kd"&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kd"&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nc"&gt;HelloOpenCVJava&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span class="cm"&gt;/** Loading the OpenCV library. */&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="kd"&gt;static&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;System&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;loadLibrary&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Core&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;NATIVE_LIBRARY_NAME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="o"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span class="kd"&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kd"&gt;static&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kt"&gt;void&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;main&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;String&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;[]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;args&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="cm"&gt;/** Printing the OpenCV version. */&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;System&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;out&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;println&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;Hello OpenCV &amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Core&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;VERSION&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;!&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="cm"&gt;/** Printing the Java version. */&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;System&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;out&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;println&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;Hello to you too, Java &amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;System&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;getProperty&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;java.version&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;!&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="o"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="o"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's breakdown the &lt;strong&gt;HelloOpenCVJava&lt;/strong&gt; application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;import&lt;/strong&gt; keyword is necessary to load the &lt;strong&gt;Core&lt;/strong&gt; class from the OpenCV library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use the &lt;strong&gt;NATIVE_LIBRARY_NAME&lt;/strong&gt; property of the Core class to find the corresponding name of the library and use as parameter to the &lt;strong&gt;loadLibrary&lt;/strong&gt; method. In this case, it returns &lt;strong&gt;opencv_java320&lt;/strong&gt;. This will allow us to use the OpenCV library. After that, we print the versions of the library and Java.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="compiling-and-running-helloopencvjava"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Compiling and Running HelloOpenCVJava&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your project directory must be looking like this right now:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="go"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="go"&gt;|__ HelloOpenCVJava.java&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it is, run the following command to compile HelloOpenCVJava.java:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="gp"&gt;$&lt;/span&gt; javac -cp /usr/share/OpenCV/java/opencv-320.jar HelloOpenCVJava.java
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you should have your bytecode class file &lt;strong&gt;HelloOpenCVJava.class&lt;/strong&gt;. Here's how the directory should look like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="go"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="go"&gt;|__ HelloOpenCVJava.class&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="go"&gt;|__ HelloOpenCVJava.java&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://docs.oracle.com/javase/8/docs/technotes/tools/windows/findingclasses.html#BABBFCIJ"&gt;-cp flag&lt;/a&gt; tells the compiler to set the system property java.class.path, which is a list of directories, JAR files and ZIP files that contain class files. We are using here to indicate that we want to find our &lt;strong&gt;opencv-320.jar&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have everything we need to run our application now. We do this with the following command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="gp"&gt;$&lt;/span&gt; java -Djava.library.path&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;/usr/lib/jni -cp /usr/share/OpenCV/java/opencv-320.jar:. HelloOpenCVJava
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;-Djava.library.path&lt;/strong&gt; sets the &lt;strong&gt;java.library.path&lt;/strong&gt; property (-D is a flag to set a system property) to inform the JVM where it can locate native libraries. This property is part of the system environment used by Java, in order to find and load native libraries used by an application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This should be your output:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="go"&gt;Hello OpenCV 3.2.0!&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="go"&gt;Hello to you too, Java 1.8.0_181!&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second line may change depending on your version of Java.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did it! Well, I did it. I hope that you can replicate this in your machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To finish, I would like to point out that in the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://opencv-java-tutorials.readthedocs.io/en/latest/01-installing-opencv-for-java.html#set-up-opencv-for-java-in-eclipse"&gt;OpenCV Java Tutorials Documentation&lt;/a&gt; there's a pretty neat tutorial on how to use OpenCV in an IDE like &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.eclipse.org/"&gt;Eclipse&lt;/a&gt;, if you prefer to work in such fashion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next chapter of this journey, we will play a little with Mat objects and some images. Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="digital image processing"></category><category term="java"></category><category term="opencv"></category><category term="dip"></category></entry><entry><title>Hello World, Hello Pelican</title><link href="https://andrefellipe.com/introduction.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-08-29T01:30:00-03:00</published><updated>2018-10-03T23:05:00-03:00</updated><author><name>Andre Fellipe da Silva</name></author><id>tag:andrefellipe.com,2018-08-29:/introduction.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;A brief introduction to the site. This post was written to the sound of The Replacement's &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tim_(album)"&gt;Tim&lt;/a&gt;. You can listen one of the songs &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cbhQKffugNk"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;andrefellipe.com&lt;/strong&gt; was an idea that I had a long time ago to support my personal projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've developed this personal page using &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open-source_software"&gt;open-source&lt;/a&gt; tools, so the very least I can do is thank and mention the projects and the people that made this site possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This site is powered by &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://blog.getpelican.com/"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt;, a static site generator written in &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.python.org/"&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks to its great documentation and community support, I was able to get everything up and running in a couple of hours. Pelican has a lot of themes developed by its community. The one that you're seeing now is called &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/alexandrevicenzi/Flex"&gt;Flex&lt;/a&gt; and it was developed by another brazilian, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.alexandrevicenzi.com/"&gt;Alexandre Vicenzi&lt;/a&gt;. I specially love how it looks in a mobile device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would also like to thank the second best student of the Federal University of Rio Grande do Norte, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/vitorsr"&gt;Vítor Saraiva&lt;/a&gt;. His &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://vitorsr.github.io/"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; was the source of inspiration to this idea.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Introduction"></category><category term="pelican"></category></entry></feed>