<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Andre Fellipe - tv</title><link href="https://andrefellipe.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://andrefellipe.com/feeds/tv.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://andrefellipe.com/</id><updated>2025-10-13T15:28:00-03:00</updated><subtitle>made on the internet</subtitle><entry><title>Spider-Man: The Animated Series (Season 04)</title><link href="https://andrefellipe.com/spider-man-season-four.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-10-13T15:08:00-03:00</published><updated>2023-10-13T15:08:00-03:00</updated><author><name>Andre Fellipe da Silva</name></author><id>tag:andrefellipe.com,2025-10-13:/spider-man-season-four.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Once again, we're back. I'll finish these reviews of the show until the end of 2025. I promise. This post was written to the sound of Alt J's &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/An_Awesome_Wave"&gt;An Awesome Wave&lt;/a&gt;. You can listen one of the songs &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rVeMiVU77wo"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After the best episode of the series, Season 4 of &lt;strong&gt;Spider-Man: TAS&lt;/strong&gt; has high expectations. Can the show keep the momentum? Let's find out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bob Richardson directed all episodes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="guilty"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guilty&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the first episode of the fourth season of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/15-01-S04E01-guilty.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;I hope you'll change your mind about taking pictures of Spider-Man, Peter. I've never been more convinced in my life that Spider-Man is a true hero. I know his job's not easy, but he's exactly what this city, this world, needs right now. I hope he never gives up.&amp;quot; - Joseph Robertson&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Story by&lt;/strong&gt;: John Semper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teleplay by:&lt;/strong&gt; Larry Brody and Meg McLaughlin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guilt is a strong sentiment that drives Spider-Man for most of the premiere. Flashbacks from the previous Season Finale start us this season and what follows is a conflicted Spider-Man that thinks that his antics do more harm than good. We went in this place before in the series, but this time the stakes are higher since we are talking about the disappearance of Mary Jane. To surpass this, a small redemption story is a good starting point. Kingpin sets up Robbie and Spider-Man partners with &amp;quot;Jigsaw&amp;quot; Jameson to save him. The dynamic between the journalist and the hero here is great, generating some laughs along the way. While the episode is nice, it also feels like we already have this discussion about how Spider-Man does good to the world before in the series, so I believe that not much was added to the topic here. A solid start to the season to get us started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-cat"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cat&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the second episode of the fourth season of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/15-02-S04E02-cat.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;Why do I always fall for mysterious men? Jason, Michael, Spider-Man. Men who are wrapped in the dark blanket of the night.&amp;quot; - Felicia Hardy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Story by&lt;/strong&gt;: John Semper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teleplay by&lt;/strong&gt;: Sean Catherine Derek.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Felicia Hardy was always an interesting presence throughout the series, but it is about to receive a new spotlight as the Black Cat. This episode starts this, with her family once again in trouble. The way the writing combines a Kingpin plot with Captain America's origin and the Hardy family is really well done and a clever connection between stories. I am excited to have this new approach on the character and this kickoff of the plot shows how the show can take a side character and make a interesting storyline with deep connections to well-known comic book arcs. The lowlight here was Dr. Octopus just being a hired gun for the Kingpin, even though we know that the character can be much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-black-cat"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Black Cat&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the third episode of the fourth season of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/15-03-S04E03-black.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;Ever hear the phrase, divide and conquer?&amp;quot; - Black Cat&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Story by&lt;/strong&gt;: John Semper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teleplay by&lt;/strong&gt;: Marty Isenberg, Robert N. Skir, and Sean Catherine Derek.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Black Cat is now officially with us. Kingpin develops the serum to create the Super Soldiers and applies it on Felicia Hardy. In this beginning, Spider-Man has great chemistry with her. The initial scene between them has great lines and tension that resonates through the rest of the episode. One of the best aspects of this relationship is that the Black Cat respected Spider-Man's identity and he does not know who she is, which makes the partnership more fun. Overall, Kingpin's plan to create super criminals is a little stupid and one of the instances where his idea makes little sense and is needed only to advance the plot. Even with a soft story, the moments between the main characters and the Hardy family more than make things up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-return-of-kraven"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Return of Kraven&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the fourth episode of the fourth season of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/15-04-S04E04-kraven.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;There's nothing that beast can dish out that this beauty can't handle.&amp;quot; - Black Cat&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Written by&lt;/strong&gt;: Meg McLaughlin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good story needs a good villain. While the addition of the Black Cat is adding a lot to the show, Kraven returning does not do much for me. The best part of this episode is Spider-Man turning away the Black Cat for fear of hurting someone once again. Our hero turns to bitterness in multiple points of the episode while trying to understand why Kraven is back. The plot involving the Hunter is not that interesting, but the character moments from all characters here makes up for it. The ending is also an interesting part, with Peter moving in with Harry even after their issues throughout the last season. An enjoyable - even though forgettable - installment of the show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="tv"></category><category term="tv"></category><category term="spider-man"></category></entry><entry><title>Spider-Man: The Animated Series (Season 03)</title><link href="https://andrefellipe.com/spider-man-season-three.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-03-16T22:18:00-03:00</published><updated>2025-10-13T15:28:00-03:00</updated><author><name>Andre Fellipe da Silva</name></author><id>tag:andrefellipe.com,2025-03-16:/spider-man-season-three.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;I'm back again. And I ditched Spotify. This post was written to the sound of Rita Lee's &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fruto_Proibido"&gt;Fruto Proibido&lt;/a&gt;. You can listen one of the songs &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JJhKbpjfXnQ"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Season three, here we go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bob Richardson directed all episodes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="doctor-strange"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doctor Strange&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the first episode of the third season of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/14-01-S03E01-strange.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;You should take that act to Vegas. All he needs is a couple of tigers.&amp;quot; - Spider-Man&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Written by:&lt;/strong&gt; John Semper and Mark Hoffmeier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Family is a fundamental aspect of any iteration of the Spider-Man story and the season premiere of the third season brings this to the forefront. Mary Jane is kidnapped and Spider-Man is looking for her. After a season of sci-fi horror, we encounter the magic world of Doctor Strange, Wong, Baron Mordo, and Dormammu. This was a great change of pace for the series, an episode where Spider-Man's powers were pretty uneffective in combat. Mary Jane that assumes the protagonism here, dealing with her abusive father's past and being brainwashed because of that. It was a great character arc for Mary Jane to overcome by herself the mind control and break free of her past. This allowed her to be a protagonist and not just a damsel in distress. The episode also introduces Doctor Strange in great fashion, telling us about its story with Mordo through quick and productive flashbacks. The character added a lot to the episode, with Spider-Man's reactions to the world of magic being the humorous highlight here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="make-a-wish"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make a Wish&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the second episode of the third season of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/14-02-S03E02-madame.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;I am not your enemy, Peter Parker. You are.&amp;quot; - Madame Web&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Story by&lt;/strong&gt;: John Semper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teleplay by&lt;/strong&gt;: Mark Hoffmeier, Elliot S. Maggin, and Meg McLaughlin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Make a Wish&lt;/em&gt; is a brilliant episode. It combines three of the best stories from Spider-Man into one and delivers the content in unforgettable fashion. We see Peter Parker giving up on being Spider-Man (&amp;quot;Spider-Man No More!&amp;quot;), Madame Web making her presence known and showing how important of a character it will be, the hero's origin story and a recollection of the classic &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Kid_Who_Collects_Spider-Man"&gt;The Kid Who Collects Spider-Man&lt;/a&gt;. This combination shows a powerful story where we are reminded that Peter Parker has personal misfortunes amid his heroism. It just shows that his struggles will never be over as long as he embraces his responsibilities. The only negative here for me are the dream sequences in the origin story. I was never a fan of the dream sequences and Peter showing up as an actual spider is more gross than entertaining. But even with that, this episode still ranks highly on my list of favorite episodes of the series. The story, the chemistry with Taina, Madame Web confronting Peter, Doctor Octopus gaining the upperhand and outsmarting the hero... Everything positive meshes so well that brings the episode into a different bracket of great episodes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="attack-of-the-octobot"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attack of the Octobot&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the third episode of the third season of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/14-03-S03E03-taina.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;I do know who I am now. And I'll be ready. And it's all because of the faith of a little girl that's more of a superhero than I'll ever be.&amp;quot; - Spider-Man&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Written by&lt;/strong&gt;: Meg McLaughlin and John Semper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spider-Man loses his memory and begins an uneasy alliance with Dr. Octopus before Taina saves him. While a weird story, the emotional punches that shown in the relationship between Spider-Man and Taina makes this a sweet conclusion to the arc. The episode relies on Spider-Man being confused about his identity, both because of amnesia as well as because of his previous disappointments, which led the protagonist to abandon his superhero persona. This is a deep arc that resonates with Madame Web's talks about a bigger challenge coming for our hero and those moments are the heart of the episode. My least favorite aspect are the robberies with Dr. Octopus, but it is understandable why they are needed. Our glimpses on the cab drivers community helping our hero are a delight, though, showing how much of an impact Peter Parker has on the city. This episode is a nice collection of sweet moments, ending with a darker tone that only amplifies the meaning of all that we just witnessed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="enter-the-green-goblin"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enter the Green Goblin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the fourth episode of the third season of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/14-04-S03E04-goblin.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;Alright, Hobgo... You are not the Hobgoblin!&amp;quot; - Spider-Man&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Story by&lt;/strong&gt;: John Semper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teleplay by&lt;/strong&gt;: Marty Isenberg and Robert N. Skir.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third season of &lt;strong&gt;Spider-Man: TAS&lt;/strong&gt; has every episode with the prefix The Sins of the Fathers. In the Season Premiere, it was Mary Jane that had to deal with the trauma that her father caused in her life. Here, we take a closer look at Harry, which brings us the debut of the Green Goblin. It is an interesting choice to have one of the main antagonists debut almost as an one-off, but this takes nothing from the episode. The Green Goblin establishes himself as a menace out of the gate kidnapping Oscorp's Board of Directors and Mary Jane. The insanity of the character is well displayed and the action sequences with Spider-Man are well crafted. It is interesting that everything is presented as the result of an accident and Norman Osborn returns to normal at the end of the episode. The Green Goblin has much more importance in future episodes and his introduction is just a small bit of much more evil things that will come from the character.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="rocket-racer"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rocket Racer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the fifth episode of the third season of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/14-05-S03E05-rocket.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;Yes, ladies and gentlemen, it's Robert &amp;quot;The Rocket&amp;quot; Farrell slashin' up the sidewalk! Will the curb be a problem? No way! He too stoped to be stopped! Radical aerial! The crowd goes wild! He swings the stairs like a pro! And then for the grand finale...&amp;quot; - Robert Farrell&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Story by&lt;/strong&gt;: John Semper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teleplay by&lt;/strong&gt;: Doug Booth and Mark Hoffmeier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are not your thoughts. Whenever a thought comes to your head, good or bad, you have the power to act or not upon it. Robert Farrell struggles with bad thoughts throughout this episode. If his past already condemns him as a criminal, why should he try to be a better person? Farrell almost gives in to the dark side on multiple occasions, but decides against it at the last minute. His caring love for his mother makes him to strive towards being a better person, even with hiccups. Seeing him learn that while fighting against what seems like the whole world is what makes this episode a surprise this season. Even though it puts Spider-Man and Peter as afterthoughts, Farrell more than carries his share of the bargain. The villainous Big Wheel is far from an interesting rival, but it serves its purpose here. The moral dilemma is what carries this episode. A boy - without a father, important to note - finally deciding who he is and choosing his abilities&amp;nbsp;to&amp;nbsp;do&amp;nbsp;good. This is generally considered the worst episode of the series by the fans, but I will not go that far. It could be a worse execution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="framed"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Framed&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the sixth episode of the third season of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/14-06-S03E06-framed.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;They say justice is also blind. So I like to think it gives me a leg up on the competition. Judging from what you've gotten yourself into, we're going to need every bit of help we can get.&amp;quot; - Matt Murdock&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Story by&lt;/strong&gt;: John Semper and Mark Hoffmeier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teleplay by&lt;/strong&gt;: Brooks Wachtel and Cynthia Harrison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daredevil arrives!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the best parts of the show is how Spider-Man interacts with other characters from the Marvel universe. We saw great episodes with X-Men and Blade, for instance, but Daredevil - at least for me - hits a special cord. My two favorite superheroes sharing the screen is a great recipe for a special episode. Here, Peter is accused of treason against the United States government and Matt Murdock is his lawyer since the Kingpin is involved in the scheme. This is one of the most fast-paced episodes of the show so far and packs a lot of information: besides the conspiracy plot, we also get Daredevil's origin story. It is incredible how Daredevil steals the show while he shares the spotlight with our protagonist, showing the strength of the character and its search for justice. The fact he does not know who Spider-Man is only makes things more interesting, since it puts them in a adversary position, creating great tension to end the first part of the two-parter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-man-without-fear"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Man Without Fear&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the seventh episode of the third season of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/14-07-S03E07-fear.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;Sacrifices must be made.&amp;quot; - Kingpin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Story by&lt;/strong&gt;: John Semper and Mark Hoffmeier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teleplay by&lt;/strong&gt;: Sean Catherine Derek.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one where Kingpin almost gets caught. One of the final moments of this episode with the fakeout where Spider-Man and Daredevil get the villain just so to be shown that was the Chameleon was incredibly well done. Well, all of &lt;strong&gt;The Man Without Fear&lt;/strong&gt; follows this pattern, concluding one of the best arcs of the series and raising the stakes: Peter Parker now knows that Wilson Fisk is not who he seems to be. This changes the dynamic of the show moving forward and the final scene puts this directly in our faces. But even before these final moments, the episode showed great moments, with articulate fight scenes and another origin story. Knowing more about the tragic backstory of the Kingpin adds another layer to the character and the quote above shows how brutal he can be, leaving his son to go to jail without reply at the end. The way this episode open space for Daredevil and the Kingpin to shine shows how mature the show's writing can get, a characteristic that distinguishes the show from other similar cartoons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-ultimate-slayer"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Ultimate Slayer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the eighth episode of the third season of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/14-08-S03E08-slayer.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;But do you love him?&amp;quot; - Peter Parker&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Story by&lt;/strong&gt;: John Semper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teleplay by&lt;/strong&gt;: Doug Booth and Mark Hoffmeier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kingpin tries to strike back with the creation of the Ultimate Slayer. The series returns to the theme of the season: paternal relationships. Alistair finds that Kingpin has been manipulating him and that his father is alive, prompting the newly-created robot to turn on Wilson Fisk. This part of the episode is not bad, but hits like a downgrade as the follow-up to the Spider-Man/Daredevil adventure from the last two episodes. Alistair is just not there as a character to have that kind of spotlight. On the other hand, Mary Jane and Harry Osborn getting married and her second thoughts is a much more interesting storyline. She explaining her feelings to Spider-Man while it struggles to keep his feelings to himself is the best part of the episode. The chemistry between the characters brings life to the screen by itself, with this love triangle promising much more to the rest of the season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="tombstone"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tombstone&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the ninth episode of the third season of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/14-09-S03E09-tombstone.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;Randy Robertson! What's he doing with these punks? Is crime going to infect and poison everyone I know?&amp;quot; - Spider-Man&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Written by&lt;/strong&gt;: Larry Brody, Robert N. Skir, Marty Isenberg, and John Semper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another mix of origin story alongside a side character getting the spotlight?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, it is a formula that works, so why not repeat it? This time, we have Tombstone and Robbie as former friends, now turned enemies. The episode does a good job on stablishing the relationship between two characters that only had few opportunities of the bright lights. I liked how Tombstone was presented as a smart and manipulative villain instead of just a brute enforcer. Spider-Man playing catch-up also worked well, with our hero discovering the plan step-by-step and getting us back to the theme of the season: daddy issues! While having no season-wide impact on the storylines, &lt;strong&gt;Tombstone&lt;/strong&gt; has enough of a good story and execution to not be a forgettable affair. Bad guys have a plan to kill a story from the Daily Bugle, Spider-Man and friends interviene, Madame Web shows us the way and season 3 has another good installment. Good day at the office for the show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="venom-returns"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Venom Returns&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the tenth episode of the third season of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/14-10-S03E10-venom.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;Together again. We knew it wasn't a delusion!&amp;quot; - Venom&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Written by&lt;/strong&gt;: Stan Berkowitz, Len Wein, and John Semper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The title says it all. Venom is back and one of the show's best character returns in explosive fashion, bringing its offspring to generate Carnage. This episode is all about setting things up for a second part, with all of the pieces being put together to clearly climax in the following episode. We see Eddie Brock develop feelings for his therapist, Cletus Kasady getting caught by Spider-Man, Dormammu and Mordo's plan being executed to bring the symbiote to Earth and Stark Enterprise playing a role with its new technology. A lot of setup that does not slow down the episode, even though it is clear that the best is yet to come. And I did not even mentioned War Machine, showing up and being a strong present right away in the series. Venom is always a hit on this show and his return could not been done in better fashion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="carnage"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carnage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the eleventh episode of the third season of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/14-11-S03E11-carnage.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;That was good for an old guy.&amp;quot; - Carnage&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Written by&lt;/strong&gt;: Stan Berkowitz, James Krieg, and John Semper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spider-Man, Venom, Carnage, Iron Man, Mordo, Dr. Kafka and Dormammu all together in a crazy fight sequence was quite a cast to blend together in this two-part episode. And I believe the end result was good to watch. While it may be a tad disappointment to have this cast revolve around Dormammu and the plot of the mystic world, the execution was still something fun. The worst part was that now Venom and Carnage were sent away at the end, meaning that appearances from them now are highly unlikely, which is a shame. Venom is one of Spider-Man's main villains and his story in this show - while always great - could have been more in terms of quantity. The whole idea of having Spider-Man and Iron Man together with Venom to fight the bad guys made it for a great dynamic, which guaranteed the success of the episode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-spot"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Spot&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the twelfth episode of the third season of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/14-12-S03E12-spot.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;Shouln't you be the mascot at a fire station or something.&amp;quot; - Spider-Man&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Written by&lt;/strong&gt;: James Krieg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Spot&lt;/strong&gt; is without a doubt in my mind the worst episode of the series. Johnathon Ohnn is a scientist who created the time dilation accelerator portal-making machine for Tony Stark. Kingpin approaches him and, after an accident, he is transformed into the villain named Spot. He uses his abilities to teleport himself into any place to steal money for his research. Spider-Man is in the position to stop him. The premise is weak and the antagonist poses little threat to our hero, making this a chore to go through. The best part of the episode is related to Peter and Mary Jane getting back together and the tease at the end with the return of the Hobgoblin, which brings us to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="goblin-war"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goblin War!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the thirteen episode of the third season of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/14-13-S03E13-war.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;I must've gotten hit hard. I'm seeing double.&amp;quot; - Spider-Man&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Written by&lt;/strong&gt;: Mark Hoffmeier, John Semper, Robert N. Skir, and Marty Isenberg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Goblin War! The time dilation accelerator remains an important plot point for the series and every villain wants to get its hands on the device. Spider-Man must stop all of them, but, considering that two of them are the goblins, they may as well just destroy each other by themselves to get it. Norman Osborn going insane again is always fun and his rampage against the Hobgoblin shows the hierarchy between them. Speaking of him, we learn the identity of the yellow goblin and this adds a lot to the episode. The overall idea of pitting the goblins against each other is a creative win for the series, setting up the stakes for a very interesting finale next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="turning-point"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turning Point&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the fourteenth episode of the third season of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/14-14-S03E14-turning.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;Yes, yes. Take off your mask. Reveal your secret identity to your greatest enemy. At last Spider-Man's greatest secret is mine. What! The Green Goblin's greatest foe a mere boy?! Impossible! Impossible!&amp;quot; - Green Goblin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Written by&lt;/strong&gt;: James Krieg, John Semper, Robert N. Skir, and Marty Isenberg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best episode of the series and one of the best adaptations of the &amp;quot;Green Goblin finds out who Spider-Man is&amp;quot; story ever created, &lt;strong&gt;Turning Point&lt;/strong&gt; is a beautiful episode of television. The Season Finale amps up the tension and creates twenty minutes of magic, with the Green Goblin getting the upper hand on our hero because of the time dilation accelerator. I love how fast this episode is and how dedicated it is to settling the score between Spider-Man and Green Goblin, even throwing both of their respective families into the mix. The final moments of the episode are riveting, with Mary Jane disappearing and a lost Peter Parker seeking help from Madame Web to no avail. Now we get to see what our hero is made of, with the first major loss for him thanks to his work almost changing him right out of the gate. Spider-Man not falling into revenge and trying to help the goblin at the end even with all of the chaos that just happened is a great exemplification of why he is a special character. All in all, the season ends with the highlight and a new mission for our protagonist: find Mary Jane Watson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This finishes the review of Season 3 of &lt;strong&gt;Spider-Man: The Animated Series&lt;/strong&gt;. The show added a lot of recurring elements that will still return, such as Madame Web and Iron Man, while bringing back some of the greatest hits in the Hobgoblin and Venom. We are introduced to Spider-Man being chosen to lead a special mission, which shows that there are higher stakes than what we are currently seeing. There were some special lows and the mystic world storylines did not do much for me, as well as the overall theme of the season, but the highs were some of the best moments of the series so far and the Season Finale is incredible. Let's see what Season 4 brings us soon!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="tv"></category><category term="tv"></category><category term="spider-man"></category></entry><entry><title>Spider-Man: The Animated Series (Season 02)</title><link href="https://andrefellipe.com/spider-man-season-two.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-01-22T14:04:00-03:00</published><updated>2023-01-22T14:04:00-03:00</updated><author><name>Andre Fellipe da Silva</name></author><id>tag:andrefellipe.com,2023-01-22:/spider-man-season-two.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;I'm back. Now with Spotify instead of Youtube. This post was written to the sound of Pearl Jam's &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vs._(Pearl_Jam_album)"&gt;Vs.&lt;/a&gt;. You can listen one of the songs &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://open.spotify.com/track/5XtyytAig4m3HkO2XXaL9l?si=945458a504904b62"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I decided to write here again after two years without doing it. Writing is one of my favorite hobbies and writing about pop culture and random topics was something that I missed. Since my &lt;strong&gt;Spider-Man: The Animated Series (TAS)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://andrefellipe.com/spider-man-season-one.html"&gt;first review&lt;/a&gt; only covered the first season of the show, I'll be reviewing the rest in the following months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Season two, here we go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bob Richardson directed all episodes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-insidious-six"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Insidious Six&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the first episode of the second season of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/13-01-S02E01-six.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;I go to sleep one lousy day and I wake up in The Twilight Zone.&amp;quot; - Spider-Man&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Written by:&lt;/strong&gt; John Semper and David Lee Miller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second season of &lt;strong&gt;Spider-Man: TAS&lt;/strong&gt; starts with one of the most famous Spider-Man stories: The Insidious Six. In this version, Kingpin frees Rhino, Shocker, Doctor Octopus, Mysterio, Scorpion, and Chameleon to take down our hero. Meanwhile, Spider-Man starts to lose its powers in the most unfortunate times. The episode does a good job on playing up the tension between the villains, with Doctor Octopus being reluctant to join forces with them because its own scientific adventures and the conflicts between themselves to see who gets to eliminate Spider-Man. The combination of both storylines - the supergroup villains and Spider-Man without superpowers - creates a positive dynamic, with the hero having to scape on foot and changing it to Peter Parker to avoid disaster. The usage of Aunt May to attract Peter to a trap without its powers leaves us with a tense cliffhanger for the second part. This is a strong start to the season even though it leaves use with a feeling of not much new things happening since Spider-Man is facing previous enemies that we already saw last season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New characters such as Michael Morbius and Silvermane are introduced in small bits. Considering how well the series plays with storytelling, I am certain that this is not the last time we will see them this season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="battle-of-the-insidious-six"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Battle of the Insidious Six&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the second episode of the second season of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/13-02-S02E02-six-battle.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;I'll hit them first.&amp;quot; - Kingpin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Story by&lt;/strong&gt;: John Semper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teleplay by&lt;/strong&gt;: Doug Booth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second part of the Insidious Six storylines delivers after the good setup in the first part. The most interesting dynamic here is having Spider-Man save Silvermane without knowing anything about the villain and the crossfire between the crime lords while fighting Kingpin's faction. Silvermane is no match for Kingpin when it comes to being a worthy foe for Spider-Man, but the character here serves its purpose, even though why Kingpin should be intimidated by him is not clear. The narrative plays into the &amp;quot;Spider-Man without powers is easy pickins&amp;quot; heavily. The best bits of the episode comes when Spider-Man does not have superpowers and has to rely on Peter's intelligence - and the villains' lack of it - to survive multiple onslaughts. Spider-Man outsmarting six of its main foes at the same time is too good of a premise for anyone to mess it up and the writers deliver once more in this solid start to the season. It's Spider-Man at his best and a delight for us to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="hydro-man"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hydro-Man&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the third episode of the second season of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/13-03-S02E03-hydro-man.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;I can give you everything you've ever dreamed of.&amp;quot; - Hydro-Man&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Story by&lt;/strong&gt;: John Semper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teleplay by&lt;/strong&gt;: James Krieg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first episode where Spider-Man is only here for the action since the writers decided to give the spotlight for Mary Jane. While our hero is preoccupied with its mutation, Mary Jane receives a unexpected visit from her ex-boyfriend, Morris &amp;quot;Morrie&amp;quot; Bench, who now has superpowers and commits a series of robberies to have money and win her back. The main purpose of the episode is to give more backstory to the Mary Jane character, specially considering that we only know her through the eyes of Peter Parker. While her ex-boyfriend and father storyline is abrupt, I believe that it is because the show until now did not present any story with a similar tone as this one. &lt;strong&gt;Spider-Man: TAS&lt;/strong&gt; focus on Peter Parker, its dramas and its villains with the rest playing it a low-key role in everything. This is the first time the show dedicates so much time to another character and this decision pays off for the future of the series, even though Hydro-Man is too stereotypical here as the bully former boyfriend to be that interesting as a foe. Spider-Man was not even needed to beat him. While not perfect, this was a valid effort to change the scenery for once, with Peter and Mary Jane finally kissing for the first time at the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-mutant-agenda"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Mutant Agenda&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the fourth episode of the second season of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/13-04-S02E04-mutant.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;But I don't want to be a freak.&amp;quot; - Spider-Man&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Story by&lt;/strong&gt;: John Semper, J. M. DeMatteis and Stevent Grant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teleplay by&lt;/strong&gt;: Michael Edens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the season raises the stakes. &lt;strong&gt;The Mutant Agenda&lt;/strong&gt; brings the X-Men and allows the show to take its most bold universe expansion so far, crossing over the mutants with a conflicted Spider-Man. While the previous episodes gave glimpses on our hero psyche dealing with its continuous mutation, the fourth episode of the season dives deep on this, with Spider-Man rebuffing the X-Men and isolating himself in searching for a cure. Its Spider-Man at its most serious ever since the Venom storyline and the writers always know how to hit the right points to increase the paranoia, showing the hero's fear of becoming something not human. The X-Men universe blends well with all of this, with the introduction of Herbert Landon, its devious plan and the return of the Hobgoblin sounding natural. The episode introduces and brings back elements of the show with ease, resulting in a crossover fight between Spider-Man and Wolverine that was brewing since the first minute. An excellent episode that pushes the season in a darker direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="mutants-revenge"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mutants' Revenge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the fifth episode of the second season of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/13-05-S02E05-revenge.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;I had to be reminded that when I'm in trouble I'm not alone. I need to turn to my friends.&amp;quot; - Spider-Man&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Story by&lt;/strong&gt;: John Semper and Michael Edens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teleplay by&lt;/strong&gt;: Francis Moss and Ted Pedersen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spider-Man is a lonely hero. While he has partners that can help him when a dangerous situation arise, he must hide its identity to protect the people close to him. His financial situation is not the best. He has to deal the death of Uncle Ben in his mind. He is not a part of a superhero team. Peter Parker carries the weight of the world in his shoulders and that's why we love him so much. &lt;strong&gt;Mutants' Revenge&lt;/strong&gt; reminds our hero that he can get help from his friends when the going gets tough. In the episode, Spider-Man has to make amends with the X-Men to beat Herbert Landon and the Hobgoblin and finds a possible path to cure its mutation. The way the episode starts with a fight with Wolverine and ends with a green monster while also putting the Hobgoblin in the mix is quite fun and guarantees the action throughout the twenty minutes. Also, the banter with Wolverine goes as well as one can expect. Our heros band together to beat the villain, New York survives once again. Even with this, the final moment is the show in one of its most poignant moments so far: why Spider-Man took so long to go for a friend's help? Why does he have to deal with all that is going on his mind alone? Maybe he has not. That's what this episode is all about. Let's see if it worked in the next one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="morbius"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morbius&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the sixth episode of the second season of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/13-06-S02E06-morbius.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;I need more plasma.&amp;quot; - Michael Morbius&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Story by&lt;/strong&gt;: John Semper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teleplay by&lt;/strong&gt;: Brynne Stephens and Lydia Marano.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, it did not. &lt;strong&gt;Morbius&lt;/strong&gt; becomes a vampire-like creature after messing with Spider-Man's blood and the neogenic recombinator. This leaves Spider-Man wondering why everything related to him is poison to his closest people, triggering him to drink the serum that Dr. Crawford made. Then the mutation on his body accelerates instead of curing him. Voilá, we have Peter Parker with four extra arms and my childhood was ruined as soon as I finished this episode. This is a another great installment of the season, transforming Michael Morbius from creepy guy to a tragic figure in love with Felicia Hardy. The amount of tragedies in the second year of the show keeps increasing and it's interesting how the writers can introduce a character like Morbius in a subtle way and a couple of episodes later transform him in one of the series most compelling characters. It's interesting how the good the fight scenes here are, the first with a couple of common robbers almost taking Spider-Man out in a funny bit and the one with Morbius showing our hero not even fighting him, but trying to save him. Considering where we were in the sixth episode of the light-hearted first season, we can see here how much the show has already matured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="enter-the-punisher"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enter the Punisher&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the seventh episode of the second season of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/13-07-S02E07-punisher.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;Let's just say that you don't own the franchise on weirdness.&amp;quot; - Spider-Man&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Written by&lt;/strong&gt;: John Semper and Carl Potts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hunt is on. Punisher shows up to get Spider-Man thinking the six-arms wall crawler kidnapped Morbius. The introduction of the character does seem out of the blue at the start, but enough context is given for us to move forward. This is the episode where Spider-Man mutates into Man-Spider during its fight with Punisher as the cliffhanger. Meanwhile, Morbius is still hungry for plasma. Mary Jane is angry at Peter for not accepting a date with her. A lot of moving parts here. The episode has a great ending, but, overall, it is uneven because the Punisher sounds too much like generical tough guy here. The way the character is presented and its motivation to take out Spider-Man are not convincing, even though the action is good. The episode hits the necessary notes to advance the story and Spider-Man with six arms and as Man-Spider are nice visuals, but after the previous episodes, this was a downgrade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="duel-of-the-hunters"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Duel of the Hunters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the eight episode of the second season of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/13-08-S02E08-hunters.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;I looked at the devil square in the eyes... And I blinked.&amp;quot; - The Punisher&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Written by&lt;/strong&gt;: John Semper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Man-Spider storyline reaches a conclusion in explosive fashion, with all the different players involved - Man-Spider, Morbius, Kraven, and Punisher - battling it out in some shape or form during the twenty minutes. It's interesting how the writers combine two characters that were not interesting at first - Punisher and Kraven - and create a positive dynamic with them. This happens because this episode focus on the human side of them instead of the stereotypical characterization that both of them had in previous installments of the series. This is the episode where Spider-Man has almost no dialogue because the of the Man-Spider mutation, so other characters have a better chance to shine. It's one of the best episodes of the season with a powerful message. Monsters sometimes are true victims and we should not give up on people because of our previous experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="blade-the-vampire-hunter"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blade, the Vampire Hunter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the ninth episode of the second season of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/13-09-S02E09-blade.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;Is there a vampire convention in town?&amp;quot; - Spider-Man&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Written by&lt;/strong&gt;: Stephanie Mathison, Mark Hoffmeier and John Semper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another new player shows up in New York: Blade. And he wants Morbius dead. It's interesting how the show introduces Blade in a much better way than the Punisher, giving the character a proper backstory in his first appearance and explaining his hatred for vampires. This propels a interesting episode where he wants to kill Morbius while Spider-Man wants to save him. In the meantime, Morbius learns how to love its powers and wants to transform everyone in vampires, a rehash of the Lizard story that we saw in the first episode of the series. The fight scenes and the mythology involving vampires expands even more of the already rich universe of the show. What makes this episode good, though, is one of Spider-Man recurrent themes: how he still tries to save the world around him while everyone dislikes his guts, as seen here with the police and the people of New York thinking he is the villain. This is always a good plot device and it plays well here. Another important point is how much of the season is composed of Spider-Man teaming with other people to achieve something, as seen here with Blade. Another hunt is on. This time for Morbius.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-immortal-vampire"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Immortal Vampire&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the tenth episode of the second season of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/13-10-S02E10-vampire.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;What is running in your veins? Ice water?&amp;quot; - Terri Lee&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Written by&lt;/strong&gt;: John Semper and Meg McLaughlin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Morbius storyline reaches its conclusion without much conclusion. He kidnaps Aunt May to use as leverage to get Peter to collaborate with him. This triggers an angry Spider-Man that has to rescue her while trying to save Morbius. Meanwhile, Blade and Detective Terri Lee fall in love. This is an episode where a lot of things happen, but they do not have a clear-cut sense of finality, a novel concept for the show. Morbius mutates further into a bat and flies away, Blade goes as well and Peter is relieved since Aunt May is not hurt. Also, Mary Jane finally has enough of him and chooses Harry Osborn. My biggest disappointment with this episode is that it appears to leverage the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/If_This_Be_My_Destiny...!"&gt;If This Be My Destiny...!&lt;/a&gt; moment from the comics when it puts Aunt May in danger, but does it so in a half-assed manner, with the classic panel where Spider-Man uses its willpower to scape from danger being used in a Morbius confrontation with almost no dramatic effect. Considering that it is one of the comics most idolized arcs, being used here in such an unconvincing way is what keeps this episode from being great, even though the conflict between Blade, Spider-Man and Morbius creates great action scenes, with Peter desperate to keep the vampire away from his loved ones. Putting Peter's friends and family in the heat of Spider-Man's battles is one of Spider-Man best storytelling devices and &lt;strong&gt;The Immortal Vampire&lt;/strong&gt; uses it for a good effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="tablet-of-time"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tablet of Time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the eleventh episode of the second season of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/13-11-S02E11-tablet.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;Speak for yourself, bugboy. I don't breathe.&amp;quot; - Tombstone&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Written by&lt;/strong&gt;: Mark Hoffmeier, Stan Berkowitz and John Semper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one where everybody is kidnapped. The crime lords showdown is back on the spotlight in &lt;strong&gt;Tablet of Time&lt;/strong&gt;. Kingpin and Silvermane are after an ancient artifact known as the Tablet of Time, which has the special power of restore the youth. Dr. Connors and Spider-Man are caught in the middle of this and we have new super robots and new villains - Tombstone and Alisa Silver - to deal with. This episode does a lot of preparation for the final episodes of the season, which the Tablet of Time heavily influences, so the most important parts here are the small character studies that we get a glimpse of. Kingpin has troubles in his marriage since his wife is no longer interested in his line of work. Peter tries to get over Mary Jane and Harry Osborn together and falls right into Alisa Silver's trap. Dr. Connor has to hide away the Lizard once again. While not a groundbreaking or memorable effort, the episode does an appropriate job to setup what comes next on the show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="ravages-of-time"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ravages of Time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the twelfth episode of the second season of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/13-12-S02E12-ravages.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;I want to see who is behind the mask.&amp;quot; - Silvermane&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Written by&lt;/strong&gt;: Mark Hoffmeier, Stan Berkowitz and John Semper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that's a monkey's paw. Silvermane reaches its goal for youth, but too much of it came through. The best part of &lt;strong&gt;Ravages of Time&lt;/strong&gt; is seeing Silvermane as a baby after all of the hoops to get the Tablet of Time and how Kingpin disposes of it as soon as it acquires for being a reminder of his marriage's problems. The overall sense of waste of time from both villains after the endeavor has a weird humor to it. There were chases, hostage exchanges, scientific experiments and a lot of fighting and nothing was accomplished. Well, at least not for the bad guys, but surprisingly we finished an episode where Spider-Man ends in a place better than where he was at the start, with Dr. Connors being better after receiving the rays from the Tablet of Time. Our hero, though, is still without a cure for its mutation, but at least seeing his friend not suffering is a bright spot in the gloomy atmosphere of the season. This is the weakest storyline of the season - Hydron-Man was a self-contained episode - but we are still advancing towards a finale where Spider-Man still has its unresolved mutation to solve it. While it seems like we are running out of gas in the story and the writers are covering this with crossovers and new characters for the sake of it, the show has earned enough credit for us to have better hope for the final two episodes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="shriek-of-the-vulture"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shriek of the Vulture&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the thirteenth episode of the second season of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/13-13-S02E13-vulture.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;She definitely likes you, pal, so she can't be that smart.&amp;quot; - Peter Parker&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Written by&lt;/strong&gt;: John Semper, Gilles Wheeler and Eyelyn A. R. Gabai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the surprise of all, Flash Thompson saves Spider-Man from the Vulture. This episode is an interesting introduction to a member of the rogues gallery that was not yet introduced. The Vulture shares in part the motivations of Silvermane in the previous episodes: have more youth and take out Norman Osborn for the attempted takeover of his company. While the fights and the cliffhanger are fun, the most interesting aspect of the episode is Flash officially going from a bully to a all-american-kind-of-a-buffoon type of hero. His pairing with Debra Whitman works well and the romance between them plays out in natural fashion for a couple of characters that we are not that close in the show. The season goes for its season finale with less tension and darkness than its middle part. Considering that we saw Man-Spider this season, Peter Parker getting old from the hands of the Vulture lacks the drama of the previous storyline. This final stretch of the show's second year is not bad by any means, it just suffers from having to follow-up a strong beginning and middle part of the season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-final-nightmare"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Final Nightmare&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the fourteenth episode of the second season of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/13-14-S02E14-nightmare.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;I guess we old folks have to stick together.&amp;quot; - Spider-Man&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;I had no idea you were a senior citizen.&amp;quot; - Old Lady&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;It's the job. It ages you.&amp;quot; - Spider-Man&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Written by&lt;/strong&gt;: John Semper and Sandy Fries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The neogenic nightmare is over. The second season ends in a high note with the Vulture absorbing Spider-Man's mutation and our hero finally being cured after Dr. Connors saves him. But, unfortunately, nothing really good happens with Peter Parker without bad news following it up. Mary Jane mysteriously disappears and this is how the second season ends. Peter can't catch a break. From this last bunch of episodes, this is the best one. Ironically, it's another instance of where the writers combine different villains and characters in a confrontation - Scorpion, Vulture, Lizard and Spider-Man - for multiple reasons, but this one feels more natural thanks to each character having a motivation to use the neogenic recombinator. The irony of the Vulture having the Man-Spider mutation is an interesting twist and another fun monkey's paw moment from the show, but the adventures of an old Peter Parker is my favorite part of the season finale, specially when he has to confront a couple of burglars in an alley. It's a fun episode with a cliffhanger ending that already causes interest for the third season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's it. It's been a pleasure to cover the second season of &lt;strong&gt;Spider-Man: TAS&lt;/strong&gt;. The season is darker, works in a much more serious tone and shows a series more comfortable with its storytelling style. The first half is one of the show's best runs and while the final episodes do not have the same excitement, they are solid enough to make this a great season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, let's go on to season three.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;Thank you for giving me back my life. What a beautiful day this is gonna be! I feel lucky to be alive. And lucky of being who I am: Spider-Man.&amp;quot; - Spider-Man&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="tv"></category><category term="tv"></category><category term="spider-man"></category></entry><entry><title>Spider-Man: The Animated Series (Season 01)</title><link href="https://andrefellipe.com/spider-man-season-one.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-01-30T22:34:00-03:00</published><updated>2021-01-30T22:34:00-03:00</updated><author><name>Andre Fellipe da Silva</name></author><id>tag:andrefellipe.com,2021-01-30:/spider-man-season-one.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Spider-Man is my favorite superhero and the 1994 TV series was my introduction to the character as a young child. I decided to rewatch the first season and this is a short review of all episodes. This post was written to the sound of Weezer's &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Weezer_(Blue_Album)"&gt;Blue Album&lt;/a&gt;. You can listen one of the songs &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sRfu94lOEPo"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's said that your personal experiences make up a small part of what's happened in the world but maybe 80% of how you think the world works*. &lt;strong&gt;Spider-Man: The Animated Series (TAS)&lt;/strong&gt; was the first television show that I religiously followed. I don't even remember my age at the time, but it used to be shown on network TV during weekdays in the morning and I anxiously waited for every episode. Thanks to this series and the fact that I do not follow comic books, my idea of Spider-Man is the version of the story presented here. I'm really excited to write these small bits here, so let's get started...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;*This also explains why I prefer the movie version that Sam Raimi did instead of the more recent installments, with the exception of the terrible Spider-Man 3, since they are more aligned with this version. Mary Jane Watson &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; Gwen Stacy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bob Richardson directed all episodes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="night-of-the-lizard"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Night of the Lizard&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the first episode of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/12-01-S01E01-lizard.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;What a slimy mess. Why can't I be one of those galaxy hopping superheroes? Why do I end up in the sewers? You don't find the Fantastic Four in the sewer. Or the Avengers. Never do you find the Avengers in the sewers. Or the Defenders. Well, maybe the Hulk.&amp;quot; - Spider-Man&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Written by:&lt;/strong&gt; Gerry Conway, Stan Berkowitz and John Semper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's no origin story here. Spider-Man is thrown right into the action to deal with a gigantic reptile that is attacking people in the sewers of New York City. He learns that the creature is his professor and friend Dr. Curt Connors, that used the Neogenic Recombinator to grow back his arm before the equipment turned him on the Lizard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pilot is a solid episode. All of the usual suspects, J. Jonah Jameson, Aunt May and Eddie Brock are here and plot elements that will become major parts of the story - like the previously mentioned Neogenic Recombinator - are introduced. This is a good start that shows the difficult financial situation of the Parker family, the bad public perception that Spider-Man has thanks to Jameson and how it's difficult for Peter to balance his life with his responsibilities as a superhero. Everything is packed in twenty minutes on small doses to establish the characters and humor plays a big part, like with the quote above when Spider-Man is in the sewer to fight the Lizard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-spider-slayer"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Spider Slayer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the second episode of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/12-02-S01E02-slayer.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;I don't stick to walls, see? I can't swing on webs, either. I get airsick.&amp;quot; - Flash Thompson&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Story by&lt;/strong&gt;: John Semper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teleplay by&lt;/strong&gt;: Stan Berkowitz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering the target audience, &lt;strong&gt;Spider-Man: TAS&lt;/strong&gt; goes deep in terms of serialized storytelling, small bits of information that don't seem important eventually comes back and the plots get more and more interesting with time. The multi-part episodes are important in this context because it allows the narrative and the characters to be fleshed out in the appropriate pace. This is the first part of the first one that the series made. Since we're early in the series run, we're being slowly introduced to the big players and it's interesting to see how naturally Spider-Man makes enemies. This episode introduces Kingpin, Norman Osborn, Spencer Smythe and Alistair Smythe and their plan to take out the webslinger using robots while Eddie Brock continues his quest for revenge. Also, Felicia Hardy and Flash Tompson show up in a weak subplot where the football player dresses as Spider-Man to scare Peter in Felicia's party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The episode tries to placate too many moving pieces at the same time. It does not hit home runs in all of them and the Black Widow is never showed as a real threat to Spider-Man. A forgettable effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="return-of-the-spider-slayers"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Return of the Spider Slayers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the third episode of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/12-03-S01E03-return.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;Face it, Tiger. You just hit the jackpot.&amp;quot; - Mary Jane Watson&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Story by&lt;/strong&gt;: John Semper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teleplay by&lt;/strong&gt;: Mark Hoffmeier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a weird story to tell in a two-part episode. While the previous episode was not a hit, the story of Alistair Smythe aligning himself with the Kingpin is good enough to warrant a continuation, but not exactly right after his father is killed. It would made more sense if the writers did the follow-up later instead of here because this episode was very similar to the first part. Smythe sends robots to attack Spider-Man and everyone involved in &lt;strong&gt;The Spider Slayer&lt;/strong&gt;. Rinse and repeat. There's also a bomb that will detonate in one hour attached to our hero for whatever reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weirdly, the best moment of the series so far comes here: the first appearance of Mary Jane Watson. Just like the comics, she appears at the end to utter her famous line. I guess Peter will change his opinion of blind dates now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="doctor-octopus-armed-and-dangerous"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doctor Octopus: Armed and Dangerous&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the fourth episode of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/12-04-S01E04-octopus.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;Reminds me of Flash Thompson, all hands.&amp;quot; - Felicia Hardy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Story by&lt;/strong&gt;: John Semper and Brooks Wachtel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teleplay by&lt;/strong&gt;: Brooks Wachtel and Cynthia Harrison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best episode of the season so far and we're already seeing the slow introductions to the characters return dividends. Dr. Octopus debuts and his origin story is well presented with the use of flashbacks. The best villains are normally the ones that truly believe that what they're doing is for the greater good and Dr. Octopus is positioned as such here, obsessed with his experiment and kidnapping Felicia Hardy to get revenge on the Hardy family for refusing to support his work and to obtain money to fund it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The script meshes well the protagonist's personal relationship with Felicia alongside his superhero work. Using Peter Parker as the person that delivers the ransom money is a good idea that comes off naturally on screen and the fight scenes between Spider-Man and Dr. Octopus are crafted in a convincing fashion, playing it off the fact that it's two highly-intelligent individuals using their brains to get one over the other. All of the characters are used correctly - even J. Jonah Jameson getting kidnapped because of his mouth makes total sense - and adds up to great twenty minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-menace-of-mysterio"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Menace of Mysterio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the fifth episode of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/12-05-S01E05-mysterio.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;I had the power and I didn't use it. I lost my uncle because I ignored my responsibilities. He always used to tell me: with great power comes great responsibility. If I stop being Spider-Man, who else will suffer?&amp;quot; - Peter Parker&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Written by&lt;/strong&gt;: John Semper, Marv Wolfman and Stan Berkowitz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mysterio shows up in a plot to frame Spider-Man for a series of robberies while positioning himself as a hero with the help of J. Jonah Jameson. The webslinger has to redeem himself and Peter Parker questions if it's worth it to be Spider-Man since in the whole situation he forgets about his date with Mary Jane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this episode we also see one of the main components of the Spider-Man story being brought up for the first time: the murder of Uncle Ben and his importance to the character of Peter Parker. The way the flashbacks and the Mysterio story connect is well done and we can really feel the doubts that Peter has. Is it worthy to sacrifice so much and get so little in return? Maybe not, but running away from the responsibility is a worst option. This dilemma drives the episode and continues the good streak for the series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-sting-of-the-scorpion"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Sting of the Scorpion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the sixth episode of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/12-06-S01E06-scorpion.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;I knew I should have never left Brooklyn.&amp;quot; - Scorpion&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Written by&lt;/strong&gt;: John Semper, Marv Wolfman and Stan Berkowitz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;J. Jonah Jameson hires a low-level crook named Marc Gargan with self-steem problems to follow Peter Parker and find out about his relationship with Spider-Man. After his plan fails, he talks to Professor Farley Stillwell to use the Neogenic Recombinator to transform Gargan in a &amp;quot;hero&amp;quot; to take out Spider-Man. Scorpion is born and goes on a rampage all over New York City.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a cartoon that has only twenty minutes to tell a story, &lt;strong&gt;Spider-Man: TAS&lt;/strong&gt; puts a lot of effort in providing motivations and personalities to every character to makes us sympathize with them. We learn why Jameson hates our hero thanks to a mob hitman with a mask killing his fianceé and pushes him into a more gray area than the position as the series' main villain that he was put previosuly. Even Gargan has certain deep traits for such a simple character, his insecurities associated with the radiation from the Neogenic Recombinator drive him insane and character details like this gives an important spotlight to the supporting players. The episode is a good showing and important because shows that the writers are comfortable and capable to create an universe where there are people outside of Peter that are relevant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="kraven-the-hunter"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kraven the Hunter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the seventh episode of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/12-07-S01E07-kraven.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;Welcome to my jungle.&amp;quot; - Kraven&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Story by&lt;/strong&gt;: John Semper and Jan Strnad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teleplay by&lt;/strong&gt;: Mark Hoffmeier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that &lt;strong&gt;Spider-Man: TAS&lt;/strong&gt; did so well in such short amount of time was establish the characters in a convincing manner... until this episode. Spider-Man takes a backseat to a boring love story that serves as the introduction of Kraven the Hunter, a superhuman that was saved by Dr. Mariah Crawford using a drug called the Calypso Serum. He attacks her and kidnaps Robbie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these three characters are not that well positioned in the series' universe to warrant that much time to their story and Spider-Man is a spectator to all of the action. Sure, he fights crocodiles, but he doesn't drive the narrative. And thanks to the amount of time devoted to the kidnap and the love affair, Peter's subplot where he has to ignore Mary Jane and Felicia Hardy just sounds thrown together at the last minute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, a safari with a corny villain that ends with Kraven getting an antidote. The weakest installment of the season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-alien-costume-part-1"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Alien Costume, Part 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the eight episode of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/12-08-S01E08-alien-1.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;Parker, how on Earth did you get in the middle of Manhattan, hanging upside down in a costume you've never seen before?&amp;quot; - Spider-Man&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Story by&lt;/strong&gt;: Avi Arad and Stan Lee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teleplay by&lt;/strong&gt;: Len Wein, Meg McLaughlin, Stan Berkowitz and John Semper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three-part episode that brings this series to another level starts here. The Symbiote - and you know who - is one of the most iconic villains of Spider-Man and the narrative here does justice to the character. The best part of the script is that all of the elements that served as pillars of the series so far - Peter's frustation with the lack of recognition he has, J. Jonah Jameson positioning Spider-Man as public enemy number one, Kingpin doing shady deals and Eddie Brock getting screwed - all come together. Also, we get Rhino smashing things and stealing the Promethium X for Kingpin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This first part has an accelerated pace and gives the necessary substance to each character. It's interesting that it doesn't have subplots or other stories and every major player is gunning for something different inside the same plot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A great start to this multi-part episode and Peter slow descent into madness - almost killing Rhino - thanks to the Symbiote only gets weirder next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-alien-costume-part-2"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Alien Costume, Part 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the ninth episode of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/12-09-S01E09-alien-2.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;You're suppose to be the good guy. You can't do this!&amp;quot; - Shocker&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;Why not? I have the power.&amp;quot; - Spider-Man&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Story by&lt;/strong&gt;: John Semper and Brynne Stephens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teleplay by&lt;/strong&gt;: Brynne Stephens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peter's new suit makes him more and more violent while he has to deal with Jameson's bounty. After he learns more about the nature of the suit, he realizes that keeping it may not be the best course of action for his well-being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the first part ends with Peter having second thoughts about hurting Rhino, this one ends with the Symbiote assuming the control and almost killing Shocker, our newest addition to the rogues' gallery. Thank goodness, our hero recovers his conscience and reminds himself of the wise words of Uncle Ben. The seamless transformation to insanity of Spider-Man is the main point here and the fits of rage that he throws - including a corny one while chasing Shocker in a church - provides us with great action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Jameson has to eat his words and get Spider-Man's help to deal with the kidnap of his son - come to think of it, kidnappings are a common thing in this show - and the writers once again throw him in this uncomfortable position of needing aid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his most difficult test so far, Peter has to battle to remember that he's a good person and this story arc continues to prove his fame as the best of the first season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and, once again, Eddie Brock gets the short end of the stick. But now he has a new friend to cope with his bad fortunes...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-alien-costume-part-3"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Alien Costume, Part 3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the tenth episode of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/12-10-S01E10-alien-3.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;You'll see us everywhere, even in your nightmares.&amp;quot; - Venom&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Story by&lt;/strong&gt;: John Semper and Mark Hoffmeier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teleplay by&lt;/strong&gt;: Mark Hoffmeier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best episode of the first season and the end of a story arc that proves that &lt;strong&gt;Spider-Man: TAS&lt;/strong&gt; is a very mature show for a cartoon. Eddie Brock finally has the means to get revenge on Spider-Man throught the Symbiote. Venom appears and torments Peter's loved ones. The script does a great job at raising the stakes of the confrontation, as Venom knows the webhead's identity and is so consumed by hate that he doesn't think twice before using this knowledge to make Peter suffer. We go through twenty minutes where the villain doesn't stop messing with Peter's head and body, putting the hero in a position where he's outthought and outfought the whole time, even having his mask removed, an opportunity that J. Jonah James can't capitalize on. We jump from one scene to next expecting a breather or a transition to a different scenario, but, nope, there's Venom on top again beating up Spider-Man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This story arc is impressive because Peter gets to show a lot of different emotions in each episode, from overconfidence to helplessness. Here, it's palpable the fear that he has that Venom can harm Mary Jane and Aunt May and this has him on the brink before being able to use his intelligence to defeat the enemy. All of this is served with great action sequences - the final fight goes on in more than three locations - and a nice ending with him finally having a moment with Mary Jane while they look at the night sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-hobgoblin-part-1"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Hobgoblin, Part 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the eleventh episode of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/12-11-S01E11-hobgoblin-1.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;I want the Kingpin.&amp;quot; - Hobgoblin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Written by&lt;/strong&gt;: Larry Brody and John Semper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introducing the Hobgoblin here is the most questionable decision of the first season considering that it's a completely different approach than the comics. In this two-part episode, that decision may alienate some fans, but it doesn't prevent the story from being fun. The villain appears in a random fashion, but the narrative of a three-way dispute between the Kingpin, Norman Osborn and the Hobgoblin with Spider-Man - and Peter - getting caught in the middle provides us with an episode full of action and double crosses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a weird episode because it doesn't care much about providing a backstory to the main villain, trusting that the audience will only recognize the Hobgobling as a power hungry lunatic. The script does a good job at establishing him as a smart figure that puts Osborn and Kingpin against each other with the aim of being the leader of all criminals. The cliffhanger is not the most exciting because we know that the Hobgobling doesn't kill Spider-Man with two bombs and this drags the episode down, but at least we get a closer look at Harry Osborn - that now shares an apartment with Peter - and Kingpin - that uses philanthropy to divert attention from his criminal enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-hobgoblin-part-2"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Hobgoblin, Part 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the twelfth episode of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/12-12-S01E12-hobgoblin-2.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;This town has a new Kingpin, Osborn. And it's me!&amp;quot; - Hobgoblin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Written by&lt;/strong&gt;: Stan Berkowitz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The enemy of my enemy is my friend is the logic of here. The Hobgoblin takes over Kingpin's criminal enterprise and pays the price soon after. Following the uneasy alliances of the last episode, everything is shuffled here: now Osborn and Kingpin have to take out the Hobgoblin. They use Spider-Man to do their bidding and the irony of the webhead helping them without knowing that Kingpin is pulling his strings is an awesome achievement of the script.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While nothing is as good as &lt;strong&gt;The Alien Costume&lt;/strong&gt; arc, the Hobgoblin's arc has its strong moments, specially the creative fight scene where Spider-Man doesn't have buildings to swing his web to run away from the villain's attacks, having to use his feet and quick thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="day-of-the-chameleon"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day of the Chameleon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Shot from the thirteenth episode of the Spider-Man 1994 television series." class="align-center" src="images/12-13-S01E13-chameleon.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;I took a gamble that Peter Parker was the luckiest man on Earth.&amp;quot; - Chameleon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Written by&lt;/strong&gt;: John Semper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The season finale brings Chameleon, an international spy, to ruin a peace proposal. SHIELD enlists J. Jonah Jameson to catch him and avoid the murder of two diplomats while Spider-Man sticks his nose in the middle of everything because that's what he does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chameleon is a good villain because while he is not presented as a mortal threat to our hero, his gimmick is at least the source of funny material. The rule of this episode is to finish the season in a high note and even when Peter gets caught in a bad situation - Chameleon kisses Mary Jane while disguising as him - the purpose is only comedy. The script is smart and doesn't do a banana peel ending to the story since Chameleon actually gets caught because of two mistakes that he could not avoid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A smart bad guy, an intelligent good guy, Nick Fury congratulating him and Peter in hot water with Mary Jane... that's quite a good day for our friendly neighborhood Spider-Man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that's it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a light-hearted first season compared to the more serious tone of the rest of the series. &lt;strong&gt;Spider-Man: TAS&lt;/strong&gt; barely missed a step and delivered the goods, specially with the Venom arc. The rogues' gallery was well introduced and the Hobgoblin, Dr. Octopus and Scorpion had great appearances. Kraven and the Spider Slayers were lowlights of the season, but the overall experience was a great reimagination of this brilliant universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="tv"></category><category term="tv"></category><category term="spider-man"></category></entry></feed>