<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Andre Fellipe - work</title><link href="https://andrefellipe.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://andrefellipe.com/feeds/work.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://andrefellipe.com/</id><updated>2020-05-03T01:56:00-03:00</updated><subtitle>made on the internet</subtitle><entry><title>Day One</title><link href="https://andrefellipe.com/aws-day-one.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-05-03T01:56:00-03:00</published><updated>2020-05-03T01:56:00-03:00</updated><author><name>Andre Fellipe da Silva</name></author><id>tag:andrefellipe.com,2020-05-03:/aws-day-one.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;After graduating from college, I became an Amazonian. Let's talk a little bit about this process and this awesome beginning. This post was written to the sound of the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Top_Gun_(soundtrack)"&gt;soundtrack from Top Gun&lt;/a&gt;. You can listen one of the songs &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=siwpn14IE7E"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Wow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a ride the last few months have been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you may already figured out, I got hired by Amazon after graduating from college.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be more specific, I'm currently part of Amazon Web Services (AWS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be even more specific, I'm a part of AWS Tech U Program, a special program for new graduates to train them to become Solutions Architects. I got the opportunity to move from my hometown, Natal, to Latin America's biggest city - in terms of population, Sao Paulo. It was a brilliant recruitment experience and an amazing onboarding process at AWS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, then, the world stopped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;COVID-19 happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually spent just one week on-premises before AWS decided that I could work from home during the pandemic. I didn't even setup my workspace properly. There's probably an unplugged HDMI cable hanging out at my desk as you're reading this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not going to dwell much about the situation since everybody is living it, but I would like to point it out how grateful - some might say even lucky - I am right now to have started my career here. The carnage from the pandemic can not be understated. I got relatives and friends that lost jobs as soon as the quarantines started. Of course, as almost everyone on planet Earth right now, I'm a little bit anxious about my future, but so far I'm grateful that the effects haven't affected the program - even though anything can happen. The only thing I can do is work hard and be mindful about my health and the health of everyone around me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, that's not the only thing I can do. I can watch Married... with Children. I'm currently on season 3. Jim Halpert may have to watch out, Al Bundy is making a big case to be my new favorite TV character.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I hope that everything comes back to normal as soon as possible. COVID-19 looks like my generation's defining moment... and I'm sure we will overcome it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="work"></category><category term="amazon"></category><category term="aws"></category><category term="work"></category></entry></feed>